SIMON SIVA MULWA

P.O BOX 324 OTHAYA

Email: simonsiva13@gmail.com Phone: 0727870371 / 0737498706

Personal statement

I am dedicated and experienced in software developer with user support, troubleshooting, problem solving and software development. Self-directed and motivated and work effectively in a dynamic environment. Fluent in PHP, Python and SQL. Experienced in web app development, REST API development and user support. Vast knowledge of client-server applications and microservices, as well as installation and configuration of Linux servers.

Objective

To be incorporated into a team of learners and experts to apply my skills in the software development and elevate my skillset and the current organizational level.

Key Skills

Programming

I am well versed in PHP, HTML/CSS, and JavaScript all of which I have been initiated into at Dedan Kimathi University of Technology by my lecturers, peers, and self-practice as well. I have also gathered skills and knowledge in Python (Flask), Java Spring Boot from past work experiences. I am very skilled in Yii2, Laravel and CodeIgniter Frameworks.

Front-end Web application

I have an impressive understanding of web frontend tools and languages such React JavaScript Framework and Bootstrap stack tools.

Back-end Web application and Database Management

I am well experienced in working and developing Restful Services using different languages such as Python (Flask), PHP, JS, Java Spring Boot. I have worked with MySQL and Oracle databases.

Mobile Application

I have interacted with Android studio Development Environment.

Operating Systems

I have a very rich understanding of both the Linux computing environment and Windows Environment.

Education

Kenyatta University Cisco Academy

2018 July: CCNA 1-3

(Merit)

Dedan Kimathi University of Technology

2014-2017: Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science

Makueni Boys' High School

2010-2013: Kenya Certificate of Secondary Education

(A minus 75 points)

PCEA Kibwezi Imani Primary School

2002-2009: Kenya Certificate of Primary Education

(A minus 391 marks out of 500)

Achievements and Projects

November 2020 – I have been able to develop a number of digital

products such as; **SOKO KENYA**.

AUGUST 2019 – I have been able to develop a number of digital

products such as; Crime-Lex.

I also have a few of projects running locally and others deployed on

Heroku and GitHub Pages such as Questioner Backend and Questioner

<u>UI</u>.

Work experience

KEMRI WELLCOME TRUST (March 2020 – to date) as a Software **Developer.** Involved in software and web development and user support. Building applications in Yii2 Framework, .NET framework, REST API Services and MySQL.

AIMSOFT LIMITED (September 2019 – March 2020) as a Software Developer Associate. Involved in software and web development using Laravel Framework, Bootstrap frontend stack, JavaScript libraries and Oracle database.

TANGAZOLETU KENYA (March 2019 –July 2019) as a Agile Software Practitioner Trainee. Trained on Agile working style in the Software development world while working on different systems in the organization. Gained skills in using Jira Collaboration tool and developing in Java Spring Framework REST API services.

SOFTFY SOLUTIONS (JANUARY 2018- JUNE 2018) as a as a Software Developer Intern. Debugged and modified web applications. Built and tested highly available and modular web applications in Python, HTML, JavaScript, and CSS. Resolved computer hardware and software, printing, installation, word processing, email, and operating systems issues in office equipment.

BRADEGATE INTERNATIONAL COLLEGE (JAN 2017 – MARCH 2017) as a User Support Intern. Maintained and monitored the server room, the wireless network and other server infrastructure. Troubleshot and maintained all networking devices and infrastructure across the enterprise including switches, routers, and firewalls.

Resolved computer hardware and software, printing, installation, word processing, email, and operating systems issues.

In addition, taught computer classes and monitoring computers as well as attending to ICT related technicalities which need attention.

Interests

I like playing around with new technologies and learning what they do and how they behave when I am free.

I also like playing football, meeting new people, making new friends, and understanding people.

Greatest hobby is travelling to new places.

References

Joseph Momanyi,

SOFTFY SOLUTIONS,

PHONE: +254785339346

EMAIL: momanyi@softfy.co.ke

John Kyalo,

Senior Software Engineer,

Tangazoletu Kenya,

EMAIL: jkm.charlore@gmail.com

PHONE: +254 728 369655

Tyson Githinji Mukure,

Head of ICT Department,

B.I.C,

P.O Box 3040-10100, NYERI.

EMAIL: tysonmukure@gmail.com

PHONE: +254 714 717849

Benson Kituku,

COD Computer Science,

Dedan Kimathi University,

EMAIL: benson.kituku@dkut.ac.ke

PHONE: +254 726 363243